Guide to the Westall Family Papers, 1790-1986 (bulk 1880-1986) and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Westall Family papers 1790-1986 (bulk 1880-1986) and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Westall family.
6 Linear Feet 2,226 Items
Prominent family from Asheville, NC.
Includes papers of several different members of the family including correspondence, clippings, speeches, and writings of Virginia Westall in her capacity as aide to General R. L. Eichelberger; papers from family's various civic capacities; WWI and WWII correspondence; military records; family photographs and clippings; other personal correspondence including some related to cousin Thomas Wolfe; photographs of Asheville; Westall genealogy; some poetry, a journal, other writings; business papers including those concerning violin making and some from a family member's construction business in Asheville.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Westall Family Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1977, 1978, 1980, 1981, 1983, and 1998.
Biographical Note
The Westall Family was a prominent family from Asheville, NC.
Collection Overview
Includes papers of several different members of the family including correspondence, clippings, speeches, and writings of Virginia Westall in her capacity as aide to General R. L. Eichelberger; papers from family's various civic capacities; WWI and WWII correspondence; military records; family photographs and clippings; other personal correspondence including some related to cousin Thomas Wolfe; photos of Asheville; Westall genealogy; some poetry, a journal, other writings; business papers including those concerning violin making and some from a family member's construction business in Asheville.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Eichelberger, Robert L.
Generals -- United States
World War, 1914-1918 -- Correspondence
World War, 1939-1945 -- Correspondence
Photographs
Newspaper clippings
Westall family
Contents of Collection
- Westall Family Papers, 1790-1986 (bulk 1880-1986) and undated, (15 boxes and 1 oversize folder)
  Collection includes correspondence from both World Wars and other personal family records. Also includes some oversize items separated from main collection.
  - Correspondence, 1880-1941 Oct. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1941 Nov.-1943 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1949 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1967 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1981 and undated (Box 6)
  - Military papers, circa 1940-1970 (Box 7)
  - Virginia Westall Taylor Papers (Box 7)
  - Print materials, 1883-1980 (Box 8)
  - Print materials, 1970-1986 (Box 9)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1980-1986 (Box 9)
  - Volumes, 1910-1970 (Box 10)
  - Writings, 1990-1970 (Box 10)
  - Financial papers, 1945-1976 (Box 11)
  - Legal papers, 1790-1970 (Box 11)
  - Letterbook, 1884-1902 (Box 11)
  - Military records (Box 11)
  - Genealogy (Box 11)
  - Photographs (Box 12)
  - Photo albums, circa 1920-1930 (Box 13)
  - Photo albums, circa 1910-1920 (Box 14)
  - Photo albums, circa 1910-1920 (Box 15)
  - 1891 Map of Asheville, North Carolina (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Oversize (Opaperfolder 1)